Connecticut Soldiers Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Soldiers Collection, Burton Ingraham Papers
undated, 1941-1945.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Ingraham, Burton.
1 linear foot.
Corporal Burton Ingraham served in the 3580th QM Company, U.S. Army, and was stationed at Camp Polk, Louisiana before being shipped out to England and later France. The correspondence is primarly from Cpl. Ingraham to his wife, Gladys ("Butch") Forbes Ingraham, although there are also letters from Gladys' brother, Gerald Forbes, and several other acquaintances. A small portion of the collection contains information about the Colt Manufacturing Company in Hartford where Gladys was employed.
MSS20020077
Biography
Burton Ingraham and Gladys Forbes married on 12 September 1941 and resided in Hartford, Connecticut. The correspondence from Burton to his wife, "Butch" begins in January 1942. By April of that year he was stationed at Ft. Knox and was transferred to Ft. Polk by June 1942. A member of the 3580th QM Company, U.S. Army, Ingraham was shipped to England before seeing action in France, and for a short period, Germany. The correspondence ends in October 1945.
Gladys worked for the Colt Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Company in Hartford for the duration of the correspondence until April 1945 when she was laid off.
Scope and Content
The Papers contain primarily correspondence from Burton Ingraham to his wife Gladys. Additional correspondence from Gladys' brother, Gerald Forbes, and several acquaintances is also included. Notes, memoranda and publications pertaining to the Colt Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Company in Hartford, Connecticut provides some details about Gladys' life while Burton was in the Army. There are also several files of materials pertaining to friends or family members, although the relationship is not clear.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence ( undated, 1941-1945 ) inlcudes correspondence from Burton to Gladys, a small file of letters from Gladys to Burton and one file of letters from Gerald to Gladys.
Series II: Family and Friends Materials ( undated, 1941-1945 ) contains ephemera, correspondence, memoranda, legal and financial documents pertaining to individuals associated with the Ingraham's.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of mateirals pertaining to Connecticut history, especially correspondence home from soldiers serving during military actions. See especially, the Connecticut Soldiers Collection, Linwood Aldrich Papers, and the Carl Viggiani Papers. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
The Coltsman, June 1 [no year], October 1944.
Telephone Directory. Colt's Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Company, April 1945.
Photographs are located in the University Photograph collection under MSS20020077.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Ingraham, Burton.; Ingraham, Gladys Forbes.; Forbes, Gerald.
Places:
Hartford (Conn.)
Subjects:
Colt Manufacturing Company.; Soldiers--Connecticut--Correspondence.; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives--Connecticut.; Hartford (Conn.)--Family and personal papers.; Connecticut--Family and personal papers.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was acquired in 2002.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1941-1945
  - To Gladys from Burton
    - Fragments, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - 1942 January (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - 1942 February (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - 1942 April (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - 1942 May (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - 1942 June (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - 1942 July (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - 1942 August (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - 1942 September (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - 1942 October (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - 1942 November (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - 1942 December (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - 1943 January (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - 1943 February (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - 1943 March (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - 1943 April (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - 1943 May (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - 1943 June (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - 1943 July (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - 1943 August (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - 1943 September (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - 1943 October (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - 1943 November (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - 1943 December (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - 1944 January (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - 1944 February (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - 1944 March (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - 1944 April (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - 1944 May (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - 1944 June (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - 1944 July (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - 1944 August (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - 1944 September (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - 1944 October (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - 1944 November (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - 1944 December (Box 2:, Folder 37)
    - 1945 January (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - 1945 February (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - 1945 March (Box 2:, Folder 40)
    - 1945 April (Box 2:, Folder 41)
    - 1945 May (Box 2:, Folder 42)
    - 1945 June (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - 1945 July (Box 2:, Folder 44)
    - 1945 August (Box 2:, Folder 45)
    - 1945 September (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - 1945 October (Box 2:, Folder 47)
  - To Burton
    - undated, 1941-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
  - From Gerald Forbes
    - 1943, 1945 (Box 2:, Folder 49)
- Series II: Family and Friends Materials, undated, 1941-1945
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 2:, Folder 50)
  - Forbes, Carrie E., undated (Box 2:, Folder 51)
  - Forbes, Gladys B., undated, 1943-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 52)
  - Marriage Certificate, 1941 (Box 2:, Folder 53)
  - Photographs, undated
  - Southard, Kitty, 1944 (Box 2:, Folder 54)